# Front End Developer (Angular|TypeScript|RxJS|Node.js)

# **James Reed**

## **PROFILE**

I am a Front End Developer with nearly two years experience building applications with **Angular**, **TypeScript**, **RxJS** and **Node.js**. I am seeking a new role in front end development and am working my way towards mid to senior level.

## **SKILLS**

- Angular
- TypeScript
- RxJS
- NgRx
- Node.js
- JavaScript
- HTML / CSS
- Git

### **EXPERIENCE**

# WEB DEVELOPER (Angular|TypeScript|SQL|Node.js|NgRx)

RADical Systems Guildford, UK 2023 - Present

- Built a new basket whilst working on the new customer portal.
- Challenges included raising knowledge of SQL so that I could work on procedures used within the application. I did this by utilising PluralSight to take courses on SQL.
- This allowed me to be an asset to the team more quickly as well as participate in code reviews and testing.

# JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER (Angular|TypeScript|Ionic|RxJS|Firebase)

UniTaskr London, UK 2022 - 2023

- Learned the Angular and Ionic framework to build front end pages and components during release of new app for ios, Android and web in the first 6 months.
- Learned Firebase Functions and chart.js to build a dashboard to show login/register statistics to the founders of the business.
- Built the front end components for business and student subscription models to help increase revenue for the task board within the app by over 100%.

# FULL TIME STUDENT (JavaScript|React|Node.js|Express.js)

Northcoders Manchester, UK 2021 - 2022

- Built a user interface and an API for a news article site using JavaScript, React, Node.is and Express.
- Learnt React Native and TypeScript to collaborate on a mobile app that allows users to find local gigs.
- Best practices taught throughout including version control with Git, Test Driven Development and Pair Programming.

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE ASSOCIATE**

Salary Finance London, UK 2019 - 2021

- Handle all day to day collections contact with borrowers that are having difficulty making repayments.
- Learned about MailChimp to implement a new weekly campaign.
- Delivered weekly collections reports to wider business.

#### **CUSTOMER ACCOUNT AGENT**

Fredrickson International Tolworth, UK 2017 - 2018

- Advise customers on financial plans to align with / improve their financial situation.
- Prepare for and attend weekly meetings to present new ways of working.
- Continuously evaluate individual performance within the team to reach key monthly and yearly targets.

#### **GENERAL ASSISTANT**

Sainsbury's Teddington, UK 2016 - 2017

• Part of the team that achieved the award for new store opening in 2016.

### **EDUCATION**

- University of Roehampton, London, Greater London Creative Writing, 2016
- St Philip Howard CHS 6th Form 4 A Levels Maths, Physics, English Language, Graphic Design, 2010
- St Philip Howard CHS 11 GCSE's, 2008